https://www.brushtec.com/privacy-policy/

You are here: Home » Privacy Policy
Overview
In accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation, personal data is “any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person” such as a name, email address, postal address or IP address. Processing of personal data refers to “any operation or set of operations which is performed on personal data”.
This privacy policy sets out how and why Brush Technology Ltd processes any personal data that you give us when you use this website. It is written in plain language with as little jargon as possible. It is set out in sections to make it easier to understand.
This privacy policy was last updated on 23 May 2018.
Who We Are
We are Brush Technology Ltd of 3 Throckley Industrial Estate, Throckley, Newcastle Upon Tyne NE15 9EW. Our website address is https://www.brushtec.com.
Website User Accounts
What personal data do we process?
We collect your choice of username and your email address.
Why do we process this personal data?
Your username and email address are used to identify you as a website user and to send you password reset notifications. The lawful basis for processing this data is contractual necessity.
How long do we keep this personal data for?
This data is stored until the user account is deleted.
Who has access to this personal data?
Our website team has access to this personal data. Only you have access to your password.
Contact Forms
What personal data do we process?
There are various contact forms on our website for requesting quotes or for general queries. Every form will collect your name and email address. Additionally, you may supply your telephone number on certain quote forms if you’d prefer that method of contact. Contact form data is emailed to us.
Why do we process this personal data?
We collect your email address so we can reply to your query. Your telephone number is collected in case we require any clarification to enable us to reply to your query. Your name is required so we know who has made the enquiry. The lawful basis for processing this data is contractual necessity.
How long do we keep this personal data for?
If the user’s enquiry is unsuccessful the data is deleted when this is clear otherwise the data is retained indefinitely.
Who has access to this personal data?
Our website and administration teams have access to this personal data.
Product Review Forms
What personal data do we process?
We collect your name, email address, IP address and browser user agent string (the data your browser sends to a website identifying your device’s operating system and browser type).
Why do we process this personal data?
We collect your name so we can display who has provided the review. We collect the reviewer’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.
An anonymised string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment. Your email address is not displayed on the website.
The lawful basis for processing this data is consent.
How long do we keep this personal data for?
The data is retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. You can request that we remove this data – see the How do I access or remove my data? section below for details.
Who has access to this personal data?
Our website team has access to this personal data.
Google Analytics
What personal data do we process?
We track users’ visits to our website using Google Analytics including where the user was directed to our website from, which pages they visited and for how long, whether they are a first-time visitor or returning visitor. Google Analytics will also track anonymous user demographics including age range, gender and users’ interests depending on whether the user is signed into a Google account on their browser at the time of their visit to our website. Users’ IP addresses are anonymised. See also the Google Analytics section of our Cookie Policy.
Why do we process this personal data?
We use this data to track our website’s popularity and to see which pages are our most visited, allowing us to enhance our website accordingly. The lawful basis for processing this data is legitimate interests.
How long do we keep this personal data for?
Google Analytics data is held for 26 months.
Who has access to this personal data?
Our website team has access to this personal data.
What Rights You Have Over Your Data
If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. See the How do I access or remove my data? section below for details.
How We Protect Your Data
Our website is secured by SSL to ensure data transferred between our server and your device is encrypted. Procedures have been implemented to ensure that this data is not accessible by people without the required login credentials. Your personal data is not shared with any third party unless we are legally required to do so.
Data Breaches
We have procedures in place to detect, report and investigate personal data breaches.
If a data breach is detected, in the first instance we will evaluate the risk to the rights and freedoms of individuals. If a data breach is likely to result in a risk to these rights and freedoms we will notify the Information Commissioner’s Office within the required 72 hours of discovery of the data breach. If a data breach is not likely to result in a risk to the rights and freedoms of individuals, we are not required to notify the ICO of the breach but will document the breach and our reasons for not notifying the ICO.
Where a breach is likely to result in a high risk to the rights and freedoms of individuals, we will notify the affected individuals without undue delay.
Credit/Debit Card Details
Brush Technology Ltd will never ask for your card details and request that you do not enter it on any of the forms on the Brush Technology Ltd website.
External Sites
Brush Technology Ltd is not responsible for the content of external internet sites. You are advised to read the privacy policy of external sites before disclosing any personal information.
How do I access or remove my data?
Complete the form below and we’ll send you an email to confirm your request.
Your registered email *
What type of request are you making? *
Download my dataRemove my data
This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google Privacy Policy and Terms of Service apply.
News
New Online Shop
Brushtec has now launched a new online shop!    …
Read more »
Read more
Product focus on municipal cylinder brush.
Brushtec is producing an updated range of aftermarket municipal brushes….
Read more »
Read more
This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish.Accept Read MorePrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may affect your browsing experience.
Necessary
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Non-necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
